rogersbank.com 2014-02-26

# Rogers Bank

## Privacy Policy

At Rogers Bank (the “Bank”, “we”, “us” or “our”), the security and integrity of our customers’ personal information is important to us. We take every reasonable measure necessary to protect the privacy of our customers while providing the high level communication services they expect.

The Bank’s privacy practices are in accordance with all federal and provincial laws and regulations. We are compliant with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) and any applicable provincial privacy legislation.

 **Collection of Personal Information**

The Bank and its agents and representatives collect personal information in a number of ways, such as through credit card applications and in the course of your purchases. We may also collect personal information about you through your ongoing interactions with us. Personal information collected by the Bank is information about an identifiable individual that may include such information as:

  * your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or birth date;
  * additional information for identity matching and credit check purposes;
  * information about your credit card account; and
  * such other information we may collect with your consent or as permitted or required by law.

Consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information may be obtained in a wide variety of forms and may be expressed or implied. Express consent is given in writing or electronically, and consent is implied when it can be reasonably inferred by action or inaction of an individual. The Bank is permitted to collect information indirectly, or without your consent and knowledge when the collection is clearly in your interest and consent cannot be obtained in a timely way. In addition, the Bank can collect, use or disclose personal information without your knowledge or consent in exceptional circumstances where such collection or use is permitted or required by law, to comply with the rules and regulations of the credit card association or payment network, when served with a court order, or pursuant to any legal or regulatory requirement, to assist in law enforcement, or in the detection or prevention of fraud. You can withdraw consent which has been given to the Bank at any time, subject to legal and contractual restrictions, and reasonable notice.

 **Use of Personal Information**

The Bank does not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law. We collect personal information for one or more of the following purposes:

  * to provide a positive customer experience;
  * to understand customer requirements and make information available regarding products and services offered by the Bank and its agents, dealers and related companies;
  * to meet legal and regulatory requirements, including “know your customer” and anti-money laundering requirements;
  * to detect and prevent fraud and unauthorized or illegal activities;
  * to evaluate your application, and to assess your eligibility for requested products and services offered by the Bank;
  * to open, administer and service your account; and
  * for any other purpose to which you consent or that is permitted or required by privacy law or any other applicable law.

 **Disclosure of Personal Information**

The Bank may disclose your personal information in a number of circumstances, including:

  * to credit bureaus, credit reporting agencies and to your current or future creditors for the purpose of maintaining your credit history and providing credit references;
  * unless you have opted out, to affiliates of the Bank or selected third parties to enable them to offer you additional products and services; or
  * for any other purpose to which you consent or that is permitted or required by privacy law or any other applicable law.

The Bank may also share personal information about you with outside agents or service providers, including the Rogers Group of Companies, for the followingreasons:

  * to manage credit risk and other business risks, to perform analytics, and to ensure we have correct and up to date information about you, such as yourcurrent address, date or birth, etc.
  * to market other products and services;
  * to update credit information and for collection activities;
  * to monitor and manage fraud and other criminal activity;
  * to process loyalty credits earned through credit card usage as part of a rewards program; and
  * for any other purpose for which consent is obtained or that is permitted or required by privacy law or any other applicable law.

 **Security and Retention of Personal Information**

The Bank takes seriously its responsibility to protect the security and privacy of your personal information from loss, theft, unauthorized access, unauthorized or accidental disclosure, use, copying, change, modification or erasure. Only Bank authorized associates, agents and service providers who require access to your personal information in order to fulfill their job requirements will have access to your personal information.

The Bank retains personal information only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.

 **Access, Correction and Contacting Us**

The Bank ensures that customer information is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You can challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and request amendments as appropriate by contacting us as follows:

Rogers Bank  
Privacy Officer  
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, Ontario  
M4W 1G9

Your right to access or correct your personal information is subject to identity verification and applicable legal restrictions.

 **Changes to our Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time. If we intend to use or disclose your personal information for purposes materially different than those described in this policy, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you. Your continued provision of personal information or use of our services following any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of any such changes.

## FAQs about Rogers Commitment to Privacy

 **What is personal information?**

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual but does not include aggregated information that cannot be associated with a specific individual. Personal information may include such information as your name, email address, mailing addresses, financial information, service and equipment, birth dates and any recorded complaints.

 **Do the Rogers Group of Companies ask for personal information?**

The Rogers Group of Companies, including Rogers Bank, Rogers Cable, Rogers Wireless and Rogers Media may ask for your name, address, email address and other personal information when you purchase products and/or services from any of the Rogers Group of Companies or when you register at one of our web sites. You will also be asked for personal information when you enter into contests or promotions sponsored by us or offered by our sponsors.

 **How do the Rogers Group of Companies use information gathered about me?**

The Rogers Group of Companies collects and uses your personal information, to provide you with a product or service that you requested. This information also enables members of the Rogers Group of Companies to develop and customize products or services to better meet your needs and preferences, to service your account and to offer you additional products and services that may be of interest to you from members of the Rogers Group of Companies and other sources.

 **Do the Rogers Group of Companies share my personal information? If so, with whom?**

The Rogers Group of Companies will not release your personal information with these exceptions:

  * When you give us permission to do so;
  * When we believe that the law requires it;
  * To protect the rights or property of the Rogers Group of Companies;
  * Under circumstances described to you when we collect the information, such as in a Terms of Service or Use agreement, or in the rules of contests or other promotions;
  * To affiliated companies within the Rogers Group of Companies.

 **Will the Rogers Group of Companies use my information for direct mailings or other forms of communication?**

The Rogers Group of Companies may send you information about products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive mailings or other communications, all you have to do is tell us, either online or through a customer service representative. If you have given permission and change your mind, you can ask to be taken out of future mailings or other forms of communication.

 **Why is Rogers ID validation process necessary?**

Rogers ID validation process is necessary as part of our ongoing corporate efforts to protect your personal information associated with your Rogers account(s). By requesting information from you upfront (e.g. name, phone number and date of birth or other identification), Rogers can confirm that we are in fact communicating with you or an authorized person to act on your behalf. These processes assist in the prevention of any unauthorized access to your account information that may arise from attempts to commit fraud or identity theft. Rogers may change this ID validation process from time to time as industry best practices evolve.

 **How can I contact you?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact:

Chief Privacy Officer  
333 Bloor Street East  
Toronto, Ontario  
M4W 1G9 or email: [privacy@rci.rogers.com](mailto:privacy@rci.rogers.com)
